

Roger Almengor

• Address: Reichenstraße 36, 87629, Füssen, Germany

Email address: rogeralmengor@gmail.com Phone number: (+49) 1626290775

Gender: Male Date of birth: 16/02/1987 Nationality: Panamanian

ABOUT ME

After getting my first job in the field of agroforestry in a small company in Panama, I moved to Germany with the aim of studying and working in the field of remote sensing. After completing my studies at the Technical University of Munich, I worked in remote sensing primarily with optical and radar images from the Sentinel missions. As an autodidact, I learned the languages Python and C to automate routines at work. Currently, I am focused in the field of remote sensing for agriculture.

WORK EXPERIENCE

[01/01/2022 - Current] **GIS Developer**

GAF AG

City: Munich

Country: Germany

Main activities and responsibilities:

Development of geospatial tools for raster and vector analysis for agriculture monitoring

[01/01/2020 - Current] **Data analyst**

German Aerospace Center

City: Oberpfaffenhofen **Country:** Germany

Main activities and responsibilities:

- Processing of agricultural parcel data of the Land Parce Identification System for Germany (LPIS)
- Processing of Satellite Data (Landsat 8, Sentinel-1, Sentinel-2)
- Development of algorithms for geospatial analysis on crops (sampling, time feature calculation, classification)

[01/04/2017 - 31/12/2019] **Remote sensing expert**

GAF AG

City: München **Country:** Germany

Main activities and responsibilities:

- Technical and technical support of the geoinformation/remote sensing departments in the field of land monitoring
- Processing and analysis of satellite data (optical and radar)
- Method development and process description
- Quality control of geoproducts
- Requirement analysis

[01/02/2017 - 31/03/2017] **Intern**

GAF AG

City: München **Country:** Germany

Main activities and responsibilities:

- Acquisition of geospatial data
- Visualization and processing of satellite imagery

[01/08/2016 - 11/2016] **Intern**

Remote Sensing Solutions GmbH,

City: München **Country:** Germany

Main activities and responsibilities:

- Object-oriented classification of land cover types based on Landsat satellite data
- Burned areas mapping
- Satellite imaging and preprocessing
- Data processing
- Development of python scripts for the processing of geodata in ArcMap 10.x

[01/04/2014 - 30/09/2014] **Shop Helper**

Getränke Zimmermann

City: Roßhaupten **Country:** Germany

[01/10/2013 - 31/03/2014] **Production Helper**

Kerns Group

City: Rieden am Forgensee

Country: Germany

[01/10/2011 - 30/09/2013] **Environmental and Forest Engineer**

Forest Finance Panama S.A.

City: Las Lajas Country: Panama

Main activities and responsibilities:

- Forest growth monitoring
- Coordination and implementation of forest management activities

[01/08/2010 - 30/08/2010] Environmental and Health Inspector (intern)

Maderas Tropicales S.A., David, Panamá

City: David Country: Panama

[01/02/2009 - 31/03/2009] **Surveyor (intern)**

Ministry of Agricultural Development

City: Boquete - Cerro Punta - Volcán

Country: Panama

EDUCATION AND TRAIN-

ING

[01/09/2014 - 31/08/2017] Master of Science in Sustainable Resource Management - Focus: Geographic Information Systems, Remote Sensing, Landscape Management, Forest Ecology

Technical University of Munich

Address: 85354, Freising, , Germany

[01/03/2005 - 31/08/2010] Environmental Management Engineer Universidad de Panamá

Universidad de Panamá

Address: David, Chiriquí, , Panama

Colegio Félix Olivares Contreras, David, Panamá

Address: David, Chiriquí, , Panama

LANGUAGE SKILLS -

Mother tongue(s): Spanish

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING C2 READING C2 WRITING C1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 **SPOKEN INTERACTION** C1

German

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS -

Books, Basketball, Yoga, Meditation, Programming

DIGITAL SKILLS -

Python(Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Pytorch, Tensorflow) | Docker | Microsoft Office | JavaScript | Google Earth Engine | ESRI ArcGIS, Spatial Analyst | Definiens eCognition | R and Rstudio | NumPy | QGis | C Programming | Unix - Linux (Optimal Knowledge) | Git and Github | SNAP - ESA | SAGA GIS | Use of the Anaconda packages manager | Use of the Anaconda environment | Jupyter notebooks | vim | PostgreSQL/PostGIS

HONOURS AND AWARDS -

[10/08/2010] **Summa cum laude Awarding institution:** Universidad de Panamá